-> simplified reimplitation of  Chadderdons spiking neural model

Model:
each neuron -> dynamic unit  .  excitatory or inhibitory.
	membrane Ptential V_m
	resting membrane potential V_r
	spiking threshold V_t
	noice V_n
types: excitatory motor EM, inhibitory motor (IM), excitatory sensory (ES) inhibitory sensory (IS).

initial state V_m = V_r

stepwise use of spiking model equation: 2.3.1.1
a,b,d recommended by Izhikevich
a  ex: 0.02  In: 0.02+0.08*r_i  r_i uniformly distribute on [0,1]
b  ex: 0.2    In: 0.25-0.05 * r_i
d  ex: 8-6*r_i^^2 In: 2
excitatory  r_i=0 regular spiking r_i =1 chattering spiking. Inhibi: r_i = fast spiking  and low-thrshold spiking

noise stimulatoin = 300hz -> nochmal nachrechnen. 
V_n depends on V-M 
dV_n = w_n (1-W_m\E_n)  E_n = 65mV  V_r of AMPA synapses. for all types
w_n noice weights different for types.
	EM	IM	IS
NOISE	2,2	1,5	1,5


System Design
neuron model  -> moves prosthesis (virtual arm) -> answer every 50 ms reinforcement learning
figure 3.1
96 ES and 32 IS cells
48 EM and 32 IM cells  (24 lower EM movement up, 24 upper movement down)
48 P Cells (proprioceptive) -> population coded state angle of arm
-> Connection probabilites have to be mentioned!!

fa(IS) = 4.4, fa(EM) = 0.5, fa(IM) = 4.3 in the absence of learning: for EM cells wn(AMPA) = 2.2 and for both IM and IS cells wn(AMPA) = 1.5. 
The noise weights wn and initial cell’s connection weights w0 were adjusted, such that the average spiking rates fa (motor babble) are fa(ES) = 0.4,

arm = 1 joint  . joint angle \in [0,135] 0° = straigh 135 ° fully flexed.

Reinforcement learning:
learnable (eligibiliry tagged  , hebbian law): post_synaptic spike follow spre-synaptic one in time window tau in ms. Only ES-EM
					-> from spike learnable for tau ms

Reward: current distance smaller  than averge distance over pa time steps. (mean!! not median !). FOrmulares page 26
Punishment , higher.  Nothing when same.
-> send to all learnable synapses.
weightscale factor  w_s  (not weight) gets adjusted.
w(t) = w_0w_s(t) -> fomular page 26.
wsmax=5 ws in [0,5]
pa =2.
Implementation (nicht trennen)
one processing step represents a ms
Angle updates to prosthesis(arm) every 50 ms.  Difference of all summed up extension and flexion em fireings over 50 ms bevore those 50 ms. (network to muscle propagation time)
ppd number of spikes in difference for 1° angle change.

Reinforcement also each 50 ms. but 50 ms after angle has been send to prosthesis.
prop cells fire each 50 ms but 25 ms dispalced to angle change fireing. 

Theta is population coded in P cells. Each cell has normal distributed fore probability relativ to the angle interval [0,135]. Todo own plot. 
 approx 5 P cells per angle. 


All fired synapses get test to membrane potential, and new Vs are calculated. -> todo short algorithm

algorithm in appendix.

TODO plot firetimes. and argumentation that at least th non existing reward delay and the two sifferent delay phases give no sence. Besser wäre es die P cellen im gleichen rhytmus 50hz feuern zu lassen wie der rest. Dann neuer armbewegun, reward, pcells firing at the same time coding gets not interupted. 

-> adjustment to new target angle works only over reward, punishment
it's done that way, not every step can be biological founded.



Fundamentals:
in text: 
neuron 
firing patterns 
spiking neural networks (short)  
Temporal coding 



Population coding
actvations: izhikevich, hodgkin huxley, Louis Lapicque (also in izhikevich), 
 a trade-oﬀ between computational simplicity and biological correctness
Reinforcement learning
Motor babling


Static learning Approach.
1) T(taget) and P(current angle) instead of only P cells, TODO vllt noch experiment hierzu. Cause no satisfiying result by sebastian
2)D instead of P cells (distance)
why can't distant coding in the brain not be correct? Kein Verweis gegeben !
Reward to D->ES.
Learning Phase. Min Angle, Max Angle angesteuert. [all errors distances from 135, -135] But problem overshoot. explain this later in experiment.
D coding mixture of population and temporal coding. -> abkürzen, einfahc plot erklären. weniger verwirrend. formeln in appendix. Besser eigenen plot, gleichen wie bei D cells. Codierung unwichtig, da sie verwirrender weise ein zeit fenster simuliert welches spätr keine bedeutung hat da nur die D Zelle die feurn bestimmt werden.


SSP: proven to be helpful.  weight scale w_s bwloe 0.2 . disconnect and randomly reconnect to new cell of same type. -> connection propabilites keep same.  mew w_s =1.0 . -> in other words search randomly for working topology.

